# Nour Zeina

Hard-working Computer Engineering major currently attending University of Ottawa, with 20+ months of work experience. Aiming to leverage a proven knowledge of product development cycle and research and development skills to successfully work at your company. Frequently praised as diligent by peers, I can be relied upon to help your company achieve its goals.

403-594-9182

Calgary, Canada

in linkedin.com/in/nour-eldin-zeina

#### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Applied Science - BASc, Computer Engineering (CO-OP) **University Of Ottawa**

09/2017 - Present

Ottawa, Canada

- 4th Year Student
- Merit Scholarship (April 2020 & September 2021)
- Dean's Honor List (May 2021)

# PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### DoveChat - Messaging Android App (02/2020 - 05/2020)

- Built an android app that allows users to connect with and make new friends. Users can add each other and text privately or in a group chat. Video call feature is currently being developed.
- Developed in Android Studio and written in Java.
- Used Adobe XD for UI/UX design.
- Used firebase to authenticate user accounts, store information and to implement the phone number Login feature.

#### Fix IT - Home Services On Demand Android App (09/2018 - 12/2018)

- Collaborated closely with colleagues to build an android app that addresses homeowner's needs for on-demand home services. It allows users to connect with services providers such as plumbers, electricians, locksmiths, among other.
- Developed in Android Studio and written in Java.
- Implemented Admin Capabilities to add/edit/delete service, home owner capabilities to book/rate services, and service providers to add/edit time slots and price.
- Used firebase to authenticate accounts and store service information.

## TECHNICAL SKILLS

#### **Programming Languages** Java, Python, SQL and Ruby

Eclipse EE, IDLE and Android Studio

#### **Other Software**

Apache JMeter, IBM MQMON, PostgreSQL, Adobe XD and Microsoft Office

#### Web Development

HTMI, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Node and React

### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Junior Front-end Developer **Digital Hive**

05/2021 - 08/2021 Achievements/Tasks Calgary, Canada

- Designed and Developed UI features for v2.0 of the Digital Hive platform using React and Material UI.
- Participated in daily team stand up meetings.

## Software Developer Intern unTribe

09/2020 - 12/2020 Achievements/Tasks

Calgary, Canada

- Developed new functionality leveraging GRANDstack technologies (GraphQL, React, Apollo, Neo4j Database). Front-end and back-end development.
- Visual design, discovery workshop facilitation, and wireframing using Figma.
- Participated in weekly team stand up meetings

### **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

# Co-founder/Organizer Egy. Youth Club

07/2021 - Present

Calgary, Alberta

Tasks/Achievements

- Co-organized and participated in a Sport day event that included a lot of icebreakers and team building activities to help club members create new relationships and memories.
- Co-organized and participated in a Highschool and University info session to help guide and answer all youth members' academic and career questions.

# Interpreter/Mentor Saamis Immigration Services Association (SISA)

01/2013 - 04/2017

Medicine Hat, Alberta

#### Tasks/Achievements

- Interpreted for Arabic speaking students and families.
- Developed excellent communication skills while working as a volunteer as the position required written communication with parents about ongoing school activities, relaying instructions to students and coordinating with teachers and administration in charge.

# Interpreter/Mentor/Event Organizer International Club (Medicine Hat High School)

01/2013 - 06/2016 Tasks/Achievements

- Co-organized and participated in soccer matches for the international club.
- Mentored newcomers who needed help with learning English and adjusting to the Canadian culture and school system during the Syrian refugee crisis.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Junior Technical Analyst IT Engineering - Canada Border Services Agency (CBSA)

05/2019 - 12/2019

Ottawa, Canada

#### Achievements/Tasks

- Performed application migration from Solaris on WebLogic to Linux on Websphere Liberty.
- Managed a project to improve/test the performance of the current messaging domain used between applications by creating a local model of the two approaches P2P and Publisher/Subscriber approach.
- Implemented the Pub/Sub approach using a web service and MDB with topics on the mainframe.
- Coordinated with mentor and colleagues weekly to meet project milestones, deadlines, and objectives.
- Created a local model of server clusters, collectives and replica sets using IBM liberty to test it and document any errors I encounter.

### **INTERESTS**

Mobile App & Web Development

Study of Psychology

Soccer

Hiking